ghi-dc.org 2019-10-01

# Privacy Policy

The GHI respects the privacy of every individual who visits our website. Therefore, we comply with applicable data privacy legislation in regards to processing personal data. This privacy policy describes what information the GHI collects and how it is used, protected, and disclosed. 

This privacy policy constitutes the agreement between you and the GHI relating to the publicly accessible portions of our website. By your use of our website, you consent to be governed by this Privacy Statement. The GHI may amend this Policy at any time; any changes made that affect your personal information will not take effect until 30 days after notice is posted on this site.

### Personal Data

You may have the opportunity, via our website or other means, to provide us with personal information about you and your interests. This information may include, but is not limited to, your name, mailing address, e-mail address, research and regional interests, and the events and programs at the GHI that you have participated in or subscribed to. 

You may visit our website anonymously. Except as described in this privacy policy, we do not collect identification data of our visitors. All web servers track basic information about their visitors. When you use the site, we may track usage information that does not identify you, including an anonymized IP address, general location information, device identifier, browser type, or language. This may also include information about your use of the site, such as search terms, search results, or additional traffic data. The site uses cookies, web beacons, and similar tracking technologies that enable us to track your use of our site and make it more useful to you. Some features of the site may not work if you set your web browser to decline or delete cookies. The GHI may use service providers, such as Google Analytics, to collect information about your use of our site over time for non-advertising purposes. Your data collected via Google Analytics has been anonymized.

### Information use

If you choose to share any personal data with us via our website or via e-mail, we may store it and use that information to assist you with any questions you may have. We use industry standard practices to review data quality and confirm that the information we have for you is up-to-date. We may also store data that you voluntarily provide during GHI events in order to keep you informed of other events of a similar nature.

You will receive general information from us only if you choose to do so. Once your consent is indicated, you will have the possibility to contact us in case you no longer want us to use your personal information for those purposes. Unless you specifically consent to the sharing of your personal data, your information will solely be used for internal purposes. We will not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease any personal information collected online or offline.

### E-mail Tracking

When you receive system emails from the GHI, such as event invitations, we may collect information that indicates if you open the email or click on links in that email. This does not apply to emails sent from individual GHI email accounts.

### Third Party Service Providers

If you receive emails from us, we pass your information to our third-party service providers (for example to send you mailings). However, when we use third party service providers, we disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the service and we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secure and not to use it for their own direct marketing purposes. Please be reassured that we will not release your information to third parties for them to use for their own direct marketing purposes, unless you have requested us to do so, or we are required to do so by law, for example, by a court order or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime. 

Some of the content that you see displayed on this site is not hosted by [www.ghi-dc.org](http://www.ghi-dc.org/). These “embeds” are hosted by a third-party and embedded in the site, e.g., Vimeo videos or Google maps that appear on a page. These files send data to the hosted site just as if you were visiting that site directly. The GHI does not control what data third-parties collect in cases like this, or what they will do with it. So, third-party embeds on this site are not covered by this privacy policy. They are covered by the privacy policy of the third-party service.

### Social Plugins

Some of the webpages on the GHI site use social media plugins, in particular the following:

  * "Facebook-I-Like" or "Facebook-Gefällt-mir": operated by: Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, United States
  * "Twitter”: operated by: Twitter, Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, United States
  * "Google+1”: operated by: Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States

Social plugins are software modules that are developed and made available by the social media services. They can be installed on web pages as is, to enable an automated communication (data exchange) between the web page and the social media services in accordance with their respective policies. As part of this communication, data are transferred dynamically from a social media service to one of our web pages, for example. On the other hand, at the same time, data from the user viewing our web pages are transferred to the social media service (e.g., that of the user's computer IP address). 

### 2-Step Solution to Ensure Privacy

Without additional measures, the social plugins (see above) use technical means that ensure that when viewing, or even loading, the page connected by the plugin, data (including personal data) are exchanged between the original website and the social media service (here, Facebook, Google, or Twitter). In these cases, the user has no option to decline this exchange of data. 

To protect users of our web pages from this type of exchange of data, which is not subject to influence, and the transmission of data to the respective social media service, we have incorporated an appropriate technical precaution. This two-step solution gives users the opportunity, even after loading the page connected by the plugin, to agree to the use of each social media service (and thus to exchange data with this social media service). The basic setting of the 2-step solution does not transmit data to the social media services. This option may be decided case by case. A decision can be subsequently revised again. If you do not want a social media service to collect information about you through our web site, do not activate that social media by clicking the social plugin. 

By clicking on one of these buttons you agree to the use of this plugin and therefore the transfer of personal data to the respective social media service. We have no control over the nature and scope of these transmitted data as well as their further processing. According to our current state of knowledge, the relevant social media service is informed of your IP address and that of the web page using the plugin. If you are simultaneously logged in to a social media service platform, that social media service is able to directly assign the information to your user profile. 

In order to avoid such a collection of profile information about you, you should log out of each social media service platform. Data such as the IP address of the computer you are using will be transmitted in any regard.

  * For more information on Facebook about its data use policy, please visit: <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>. 
  * For more information on Google about its privacy policy, please visit: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy>.
  * For more information on Twitter about its data use policy, please visit: <http://www.twitter.com/privacy>.

### Access to Information and Data and Opting Out

The GHI provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from the GHI. You may choose to receive only specific communications or none at all. You may also update your contact information previously provided to us by e-mailing at the address below. In order to avoid a situation where repeated, unwanted contacts could occur, we will not remove you from the database. We will only contact you according to the preferences you specify.

You have the right to request access, modify, correct, or remove your data collected in our database at any time. You may do so by contacting the GHI at the email or address below.

### Contact

Questions concerning this privacy policy may be sent to web@ghi-dc.org or 

German Historical Institute  
1607 New Hampshire Ave NW  
Washington, DC 20009  
202-387-3355 

Last modified: May 24, 2018
